turningtechnologies.com 2016-10-15

# Privacy Policy

Turning Technologies, LLC (“Turning”) has created this privacy statement to demonstrate its commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Turning’s website located at www.TurningTechnologies.com (the “Website”). By accessing and/or using the Website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your information, including your personally identifiable information, by Turning in accordance with the terms of our Privacy Policy in effect at that time. Please also see the Website'sTerms of Use http://www.turningtechnologies.com/termsofuse/ for other terms and conditions governing your use of the Website. You acknowledge that we have the right, at our sole discretion, to modify any terms or conditions of this Privacy Policy without notice to you. Any modifications to this Privacy Policy will be effective immediately following the posting of such changes on the website. For this reason, we encourage you to review this Privacy Policy on a periodic basis.

Turning is headquartered in the United States at 255 West Federal Street, Youngstown, OH 44503. As discussed below, Turning complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.

### **Information Collected by Turning; Use; Disclosure**

Our registration forms may require you to give us contact information (such as your name and email address) and demographic information (such as your zip code, country, or industry). If you choose to register, you agree to give us accurate and current information about yourself. We may use personally identifiable information that you provide on the registration form to send information to you, for example, information about our company and products. Your personally identifiable information may also be used to contact you when necessary or desirable. You may opt-out of receiving information; please see the Choice/Opt-out section below. We may collect demographic and profile data through the Website. We may use this data to tailor your experience on the Website (for example, to provide content that we think you may be interested in and display the content according to your preferences). Turning may use cookies. A cookie is a small data file that attaches to your hard drive when you visit the Website. Furthermore, our servers may automatically record information that your browser sends when you visit the Website, and we may provide third party links in a format that enable us to keep track of whether the links have been followed. We may use this information, including your IP address, to track user traffic patterns, to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the Website. Turning may share your personally identifiable information and/or aggregate information with our affiliates, business partners, the media (for press releases), third parties performing functions on our behalf, and/or a third party that acquires ownership or control of our business. We may also disclose information if we believe in good faith that it is required by law, to prevent a crime or protect the rights of third parties, or to enforce the Terms of Use or Privacy Policy. Turning may transfer your information for various purposes, including, without limitation, to administer the Website, process your requests, provide you with information and customized content, and for purposes relating to business development, direct marketing, and market research and analysis. Information, suggestions, and comments received by Turning shall be deemed to be non-confidential. Turning shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose and distribute such information to others without limitation. If you use or post content on any public area on the Website, you should be aware that any information, including personally identifiable information, that you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of the Website, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. Turning is not responsible for loss of privacy or any claim relating to the information you choose to submit by these means.

### **Security**

The Websitehas security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. However, the transmission of information over the Internet or other publicly accessible networks is not secure, and is subject to possible loss, interception or alteration while in transit. Accordingly, we do not assume any liability for any damage you may experience or costs you may incur as a result of any transmissions over the Internet or other publicly accessible networks, such as the submission of any of your personally identifiable information to us.

### **Use by Children**

We do not intend to collect any personally identifiable information from children through the Website. Individuals under eighteen (18) should consult with a parent or guardian about the use of the Website.

### **Supplemental Information**

The Websitemay supplement the information that you provide with information that is received from third parties to provide you with a better experience.

### **Updating Information**

Any user who desires to review, amend or correct information relating to them, or has questions about their personal information submitted to Turning, should contact us at [info@turningtechnologies.com](mailto:info@turningtechnologies.com).

### **Choice/Opt-Out**

Our emails provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving Turning’s communications. We will implement requested changes within ten days of the receipt of a request. In addition, visitors may contact us at anytime by sending an email to: [info@turningtechnologies.com](mailto:info@turningtechnologies.com) or calling us toll-free at 1-866-746-3015. If you contact us directly, please let us know which kind of information you would no longer like to receive.

### **Information for Website Visitors from outside the United States (including US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor information)**

Turning complies with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Turning has certified that it adheres, where applicable, to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Turning’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>. The list of certified companies is available here: <https://safeharbor.export.gov/list.aspx>.

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Turning commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this Policy should first contact Turning at:

Privacy Director  
Turning Technologies, LLC  
255 West Federal Street  
Youngstown, OH 44503 

Toll Free Phone: 1-866-746-3015  
Phone: (330) 746-3015  
Fax: (330) 746-6863  
Email: [info@turningtechnologies.com](mailto:info@turningtechnologies.com)

Turning has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the JAMS Safe Harbor Program. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint by Turning, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Turning, please visit the JAMS Safe Harbor web site at http://www.jamsadr.com/file-safe-harbor-claim/ for more information and to file a complaint.

The personal and non-personal information that Turning collects through or in connection with the Services is transferred to and processed in the United States for the purposes described above. Turning also may subcontract the processing of your data to, or otherwise share your data with, affiliates or third parties in the United States or countries other than your country of residence. The data-protection laws in these countries may be different from, and less stringent than, those in your country of residence. By using the Services or by providing any personal or non-personal information to Turning, you expressly consent to such transfer and processing.

### **Contacting the Website**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of the Website, or your experience with the Website, you can contact us as follows:

Turning Technologies, LLC   
255 West Federal Street   
Youngstown, OH 44503

Toll Free Phone: 1-866-746-3015   
Phone: (330) 746-3015   
Fax: (330) 746-6863

Email: [info@turningtechnologies.com](mailto:info@turningtechnologies.com)
